so in this particular problem uh it asks
how many moles do 4.94 G of aluminum
represent so you're given grams here and
you want to go to moles um so hopefully
you've been exposed to this flow map if
not copy it down uh so depending on your
starting point you can go right or left
so whether you divide or multiply uh by
the same constants in the middle that
depends on your starting point so I
notice here the problem gives me 4.94 G
so I'm going to start on the right
because it says grams here so to go left
I have to multiply by the molar mass to
get to moles okay so even though this
flow chart has a couple different steps
you have to kind of hone in or and Zone
in um into which part of uh the flow map
that you need so in this case I only
need to go from grams to moles cuz it
asks how many moles from a specific
amount of uh grams all right so you need
the periodic table uh so hopefully you
have one available if not aluminum here
on my screen uh is about 26.98 2 G all
right so I'm going to start with what's
given uh which is a good habit 4.94 gr
of aluminum I'm going to just put that
over sexy1 just so I have a numerator
and denominator and then I want to
multiply by the um molar mass uh so you
need to put 26.98 G I know the periodic
table sets here 26.98 to that's up to
you if you want to use 29 Point 26.9 82
I'm just going to use
26.98 um doesn't really matter it
depends on your instructor how many six
fix they want you to use um but here the
gram has to go on the bottom because
you're starting with grams so you notice
here gram is in the numerator on the in
um in the first step and therefore you
need grams in the second step to cancel
it out and then because you have grams
already you're trying to go to moles so
the perog tells you essentially one
moles of aluminum is 26.98 G okay so if
you set this stuff up your units
probably cancels out so grams on top and
grams on the bottom cancels out and then
all you have to do is multiply across uh
4.90 4 * 1 mole is just 4.94 so my
numerator Remains the Same and then on
the bottom well I have a one times 26.98
well this one is pretty straightforward
as well the nuer the denominator stays
the same because you're multiplying by
one and then here we just simplify this
fraction uh so if you punch
4.94 ID
26.98 and you should be left with 18 18
moles of aluminum and the problem starts
with 46 F so if your instructor is super
gun hob about s fix uh make sure you end
up with the proper s fix here okay so my
answer has four SI fix 188 is 46 that's
it that's your answer for this one all
right stay nerdy don't be white